<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Ignacio Vinuales</title>
    <link>https://ignavinuales.github.io/portfolio/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Ignacio Vinuales</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ignavinuales.github.io/portfolio/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1. Hate speech detection (NLP)</title>
      <link>https://ignavinuales.github.io/portfolio/posts/1_nlp_hatespeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignavinuales.github.io/portfolio/posts/1_nlp_hatespeech/</guid>
      <description>This project aimed at developing an API and Web App that are able to detect hate speech from text. Refer to the GitHub repo for a detailed explanation of the project and code:
You can also try out the app and give me feedback on the machine learning model performance:
I made the API publicly available 😄 You may also want to make an HTTP request at this endpoint:
144.22.214.61:8000/detect Or even easier, check the FastAPI Swagger UI:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Face mask detection (Computer Vision)</title>
      <link>https://ignavinuales.github.io/portfolio/posts/2_facemask/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignavinuales.github.io/portfolio/posts/2_facemask/</guid>
      <description>This project aimed to retrain a YOLOv7 model to detect people wearing face masks. Moreover, I created and deployed a web app on Streamlit for users to test the model.
Feel free to try ou the app:
Refer to the GitHub repo to check the code for the project:
Objectives The objective of this project is to use the official pre-trained YOLOv7 model (built on PyTorch) and retrain it on a custom dataset to detect people wearing face masks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Diamond Price Recommendation (Regression)</title>
      <link>https://ignavinuales.github.io/portfolio/posts/3_diamonds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignavinuales.github.io/portfolio/posts/3_diamonds/</guid>
      <description>This project aimed to create an app that gives price recommendations for diamonds. You can use and test the app by accessing the following link:
Furthermore, a Jupyter notebook is available on my Kaggle profile to see a step-by-step, detailed data analysis and check how the ML models were built and compared to each other:
Objectives Get insights from the data by an explanatory data analysis (EDA). Build a machine learning model capable of recommending diamond prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Predictive Maintenance (Classification)</title>
      <link>https://ignavinuales.github.io/portfolio/posts/4_maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignavinuales.github.io/portfolio/posts/4_maintenance/</guid>
      <description>The aim of this project was to train and test models that predict machinery failure. Due to the nature of the application, the biggest challenge was dealing with highly imbalanced data. Different techniques for under and over-sampling were used, as well as machine learning balanced models such as balanced random forest and balance bagging.
Two models were selected, one for binary classification (detects failures and not failure) and the other for multivariate classification, which detects types of failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Credit Card Customer Segmentation (Clustering)</title>
      <link>https://ignavinuales.github.io/portfolio/posts/5_custumers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignavinuales.github.io/portfolio/posts/5_custumers/</guid>
      <description>Market segmentation is the process of breaking a large consumer or company market into smaller consumer groups based on similar characteristics.
This project aims at segmenting some active credit card holders to help the marketing department to build different strategies for each customer segment. Furthermore, after performing clustering, it is important to identify the customer profile of each cluster. Then,
Objectives: perform customer segmentation and identify customer profiles.
Methodology:
Explore and understand the data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
